# ohsin Ali Khattak

🔀 mohsin.alikhattak@gmail.com 📞 +92 323 9766988 🛭 🔗 Portfolio 🙀 LinkedIn

### **PROFILE**

I am a passionate professional with extensive knowledge of computer software and highly knowledgeable in Quality Assurance methodologies and able to perform in a fast-paced agile environment. Have hands-on experience executing Automation Testing using (Selenium, Cypress, and Playwright) while interacting with teams to ensure that the product is bug-free before it is released to production. At AntonX, I contributed to six projects, demonstrating flexibility and goal-oriented professionalism.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

08/2023 - present Peshawar, Pakistan

#### **Quality Assurance Engineer**

AntonX Pvt (Ltd)

- Performed comprehensive testing (functional, integration, regression, Sanity, API, security, and performance) for software products.
- Created automated test scripts using Selenium, Cypress, and Appium.
- Developed and maintained test plans and cases, trained and mentored junior testers, and managed the defect management process.
- Contributed to QA process improvement and operated under Agile/Scrum methodologies to ensure efficient sprints.
- Monitored bug resolution, tested fixes, and collaborated with developers to address ongoing issues from a QA perspective.

01/2023 - 07/2023 Islamabad, Pakistan

### **Research Assistant**

SEECS NUST

- "On Device Classification of Fruit Disease" is a machine learning project.
- Project utilizes cutting-edge algorithms to enable real-time identification and diagnosis of diseases affecting fruit crops directly on the device.
- This project aims to empower farmers and agriculture professionals with a portable and efficient tool for early detection and management of diseases, ultimately improving crop health and yield.

### **SKILLS**

Test Planning | Regression Testing | Load Testing | Performance Testing | Security Testing | Test Automation User Acceptance Testing | Software Quality Assurance | Postman | Selenium | Cypress | Playwright | Appium | API Testing | JavaScript | Python | CICD | Jenkins | Jira Confluence

# **PROJECTS**

2023 - present

### Pakistan Startup Portal &

Web Application

- Executed manual functional and non-functional testing (e.g., regression, load, and security tests).
- Automated Web UI testing with Selenium using JavaScript and conducted performance testing using IMeter and BlazeMeter.
- Actively participated in daily SCRUM meetings, analyzed user stories, reported defects, verified fixes, and contributed to content entry for production websites.

### **Noca: Social Networking Platform** *⊘*

Web and Mobile Application

- Performed a wide range of functional and non-functional testing (including regression, smoke, load, and security tests).
- Conducted mobile UI automation using Appium with JavaScript and performance testing with JMeter and
- · Actively participated in daily SCRUM meetings, analyzed user stories, reported defects, and verified issue

## Ewanc (Premier Real Estate Companion in KSA)

Web and Mobile App

- Conducted manual functional and non-functional testing (including regression, Sanity, load, and security tests).
- Automated Web UI testing with Selenium in JavaScript and performed load and stress testing using JMeter and BlazeMeter.
- Engaged in daily SCRUM meetings, analyzed user stories, reported defects, verified resolutions, and contributed to content entry for production websites.

### **CERTIFICATES**

- Performance Testing with jmeter. @
- SQL for Testers @

• SE: Implementation and Testing ∂

- Software Testing and Automation ∅
- Agile Testing ∂

• LambdaTest Software Testing Professional Certificate ∅

## **EDUCATION**

2018 - 2022